Summary

Fast-learning and versatile junior software developer, recently graduated from Northcoders, a multi-award-winning coding bootcamp. Track record of working in a team both remotely and in-person, with demanding schedules and fast-paced learning environments, as well as successfully organising own workload for research and execution of projects, and supporting colleagues.

Highly-developed communication and presentation skills, with seven years experience teaching English. A flair and love for languages, speaks B2 Spanish and A2 Polish. Spent 2018 managing, directing and producing independent theatre projects, podcasts, and comedy shows - organising finances, rehearsals, booking theatres and accommodation, plus graphic design and audiovisual.

Technical Skills

Language: JavaScript, Python, PHP

Back End: Node.js, Axios, Express, Knex, SQL, Socket.IO Front End: HTML, CSS, React, Angular, Bootstrap, jQuery

Testing: Chai, Sinon, Mocha, Jest

Additional experience: Adobe Premiere Pro, Audacity

Experience

Northcoders, Manchester

Trainee Developer

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Full stack bootcamp focused on a practical, industry-led curriculum. Used version control (Git), pair programming, and test-driven development throughout. In the final two weeks, I worked remotely in a team of four to conceive, research, develop and deliver an end-to-end application in an agile environment. Used Trello as a kanban board and had daily standups.

Projects

Northcoders News

Fullstack Reddit style news aggregation board. Articles can be created, voted on, sorted, discussed, with comments also voted on. New user accounts can be created. RESTful API built with Node.js, Express.js, Axios, SQL, Knex, frontend built with React.js and CSS. Tested with Mocha, Chai, Supertest.

Frontend: purpleprose.netlify.com github.com/chicorycolumn/fe-nc-news

Backend: nc-news-c-matus.herokuapp.com/api github.com/chicorycolumn/be-nc-news

Northcoders final project: Wormplay

An online game using facial-recognition for emotion detection, and Socket.io to play other users, after passing through a lobby system where rooms and users are created in the backend. Built with backend of Socket.io, Express, Node.js, and frontend of React, Tensorflow, and Phaser.

Frontend: <u>github.com/chicorycolumn/wormplay-FE</u>

Backend: wormplayserver.herokuapp.com github.com/nadiarashad/wormplay-BE

Other Interests

Learning foreign languages - further practising aquisition and memorisation skills

Teaching improvised standup and improvised comedy - developing the skills and confidence of others

Performing improvised theatre - excelling in on-the-spot thinking and performance skills

Employment

DadaABC, Shanghai (online) English Teacher

Aug 2018 - Jun 2020

Teaching young Chinese children who have little to no English. Communicating effectively and holding attention via an online connection, as well as flexibly developing curriculum based lessons.

International House, Madrid

English Teacher

Oct 2014 – Jun 2017

Teaching with a range of focuses, including Business English, focusing on meetings, negotiation, and job interviews. Flourishing with long sets of back-to-back lessons and late hours, and following a strict curriculum and meeting targets with respect to exams and results.

SKIP, Trujillo (Peru)

Volunteer Teacher and Mentor

Aug 2014

Teaching English, drama, and crafts to large groups requiring acute classroom management. Using my enthusiasm, social skills and patience to engage a wide age range of children of various backgrounds.

Bray's Inglés, Getafe

English Teacher

Oct 2013 - Jun 2014

Adapting existing resources as well as devising new activities, exercises, and tests. Managing time and keeping students motivated.

CES (Worthing)

English Teacher

Jul, Sept 2013

Working effectively with a range of abilities and ages of foreign students.

UBECI, Quito (Ecuador)

Volunteer Teacher

Aug 2013

Working with underprivileged children, teaching English as well as guiding play.

CAFOD, London

Education administrator, website editor

Jul – Aug 2011

Compiling, editing, researching, developing resources for secondary schools across the UK. Checking, editing, updating, re-formatting the NGO's website. Using my research skills and creativity to improve existing and create new resource and activity packs. Dealing with a wide variety of roles and tasks.

Education

TESOL/TEFL Certificates

CELTA, grade B

St Giles, Brighton

Higher Education

Philosophy BA (Hons) 1st class University of Liverpool, Liverpool

Further Education

A Levels: Biology (A), Psychology (A), Drama

(A), Chemistry (A)

AS Levels: General Studies (A), English Literature (A) Critical Thinking (B)

Cardinal Newman Catholic College, Hove

Secondary Education

GCSEs: 9 passes A* - B

St Paul's Catholic School, Burgess Hill

References available on request